Good morning, good evening. Welcome to
another episode of talk show copy file
path. So we're going to do fantastic
wufam language and JavaScript
mathematics. So we're going to do
JavaScript has lots of functions. Okay,
so uh JavaScript has uh lots of
functions uh exponential and logarithm.
Okay, so that's uh some of it we're
going to do and maybe not those. Okay,
exponential. But we're going to plot
some hyperbolic functions. Okay, so we
got hyperbolic functions. S cinch, kosh,
ten. Okay, these are advanced
mathematics. Now, if you don't know what
they are, don't worry about it. We're
just going to have fun, okay? And you
pick up something about mathematics.
These advanced mathematics you'll never
use in your coding life, okay? But they
are in JavaScript because [laughter]
well it's actually necessary. It's it's
needed. Okay. So JavaScript has these
functions. We're going to have fun with
Wuam language. Let's begin. Woof fam
language which we haven't done for quite
a while. Woo the most advanced
symbolic programming language. You've
never seen anything like it in your
life. Okay. It's a symbolic term
rewriting system. That's how computer
science says it's a term rewriting
system. So for you lisp coders, you
might think of it as lisp maros but a
magnitude more featurerich. Okay. So in
when you code wam language effectively
you are just coding maros. That's what
you do. That's what terms writing system
is about. Okay language. So we're going
to have fun with wam language. So look
at JavaScript
and look at the beautiful curve plane
curves. This project I did like since 20
years ago. Okay. Uh so actually can you
see my screen or are you seeing uh oh
you are not seeing my screen.
[laughter]
Oh well. So let's begin. Let's start
over.
So this is uh this is this is uh
uh juice and uh energy drink.
Okay, now you are looking at my screen.
Fantastic.
Now if you are here, say hi. Okay, love
to see your comments in real time
because we are doing things live, not
pre prepackaged lunchbox like most
things are in America.
You know they prepare look make it look
nice but so the cover looks beautiful
but the content is most things in
America kind of like that including all
the YouTubes okay so I prefer to do live
you know I you know so you are seeing
the real thing not edit and cut and just
like presentation and a very little real
content okay so we talking about so you
know so we are talking about uh doing
some plain curves.
We're talking about this spectacular cat
katenary curve. Okay. So, we're going to
show you uh we're going to do we're
going to actually start to do it. So, uh
earlier on I was talking about
JavaScript. So, in JavaScript you got
these mathematical functions hyperbolic
functions cinch kosh ten. Okay. So, if
you don't know anything about it, you
know, we just gonna have fun and and
Okay.
Okay, begin. Shall we begin? Let's begin
at the beginning.
[laughter]
Let's begin at the beginning. That's
right. Um, [snorts]
nothing nothing funny about that. So,
where is my Emacs? So, you need to Yeah.
So, yeah. Well uh but but also uh as
part of the todo I got this bunch of uh
so these uh webp image format we talked
about in the in the past few weeks of uh
saw talk show okay so you see webp
images fantastic very small in size but
these are some some of my todos you can
view them in emacs so let's begin to do
them okay that's the things I want to do
okay so you can open them now uh And
also let me mention so you can open them
in this uh new image viewer I discovered
I started to use uh this image viewer is
called glass view. Okay. Uh something
like uh uh image glass. Okay. So we're
going to uh start to use it. Um
okay. So we will and I was learning some
uh F the most fantastic powerful
functional programming language F. Okay,
that's right. Okay, let's begin. Okay,
so um so Katenary. So let's begin to
let's start to work. Okay, so go to my
code and oh and so today's talk show. Go
to today's talk show. Copy the file
path. Go here paste it and uh make it a
URL. Uh uh. Wait. How how do you
wait?
Okay.
Okay. Make it a URL. So, copy it and I'm
going to paste here so you guys can go
there and check it out.
Today's talk show.
Okay. Does the URL work?
Yes. I hope so. Yeah.
Okay. So, we got a bunch of things to
do. Let's begin them. Okay. So, first of
all, you I want to fix this um this
delete that catenary. Okay. So, let's go
to let's uh go to where where are we? Uh
go go to plane curves. So, okay. Ex talk
show talk show there. Today's talk show
is this one. And let's go to plane
curves.
uh
visual dictionary of spatial plane
curves and okay copy that open in Emacs
search for catenary
okay there show in browser there so
we're going to delete that image because
um because I'm going to redo all of them
I didn't really like this this
particular uh image you see the first
image I do for every beginning of um a
curve. Usually I try to make it
artistic. Okay. But anyway, so I I need
to redo that. Many of these you are
seeing is like 30 years old. So anyway,
so let me just do it. Okay.
So Captainary Moonlight Martin
actually looks not bad. Should I delete
it? No, I'm not sure. Um
[sighs]
the Oh god.
What? Wait. Showing bowser. So half of
katenary red. Uh yeah. So this this
doesn't really belong there. Okay. Leave
it for now. Okay. So to do kosh. Okay.
So let's talk about kosh. Let's just do
it. Um,
canary. Okay. So, can So, God,
what am I doing? God,
wait.
Uh
so there are a bunch of things okay co
function is defined catenary
curve is also known as chet
alosoid and hyperbolic cosine. Okay,
that is actually the most popular name
uh hyperbolic cosine. So let's move uh
the most popular name at the top.
Okay,
refresh. Uh kosh is defined as that the
capital E denote the natural logarithm
base constant. Okay, uh let's remove the
verbiage. um
instead of denote you see there's a
styling issue you know I used to write
30 years ago like in a academic style so
you say denote like the capital E denote
the natural logarithm base constant
but not today uh you know because today
my style changed But also because of the
internet in the past
30 20 30 years you
reduced you know you have less of this
academic formal uh verbiage like denote
like for example today's zoomers a lot
of you probably like what the does
that mean and uh it's kind of pompous
too because you don't really like do you
actually need to use that word not
really.
So you can just say means okay the
capital E means you know MB because I
actually have a Wufam language notebook.
This is something like 20 years ago.
So continue with updated styling. Okay.
So it's loading a bunch of my old uh
packages.
Oh god how am I going to update this? So
this is going to be a lot of work and I
suppose very boring for you guys. Hi
dusk zing.
Oh god. So this this is you see
I need to update this. This is lots of
old code. Can you see? So you see
uh they still work of course. But you
see this is the
but you see this is the introductory
graphics
at the beginning of the page there.
But I'm going to I need to update this.
Okay. So let's see. Uh so go to the
directory
now. Make a backup. Go to the directory.
refresh. Now let's see. So it's 500
mgabytes. Okay. Now back to this. Save
it. Okay. Now you just saved it. So now
they saved it down to uh 163 megabytes.
I mean not, you know, kilobytes, not
mega. Okay. So reduced size a lot. So
but what what am I doing now? So um
okay. So I'm not a bit um unfocused
because I have huge tons of things to
do. Okay. So uh let's just do them one
by one. Okay. Go easy. So first of all
let's just simply plot this thing. Okay.
So plot that. Okay. So just let's just
do it. Okay. So description. Okay. So
let's go back here.
Oh god. At this rate we are not going to
do much. Okay. because um because
you know so um
uh wufam code paste it here and uh paste
it there and we don't want that code uh
and okay so you want to plot that's how
you plot you can plot that function okay
and uh what is the range let's say
3 to Three seems like a good range.
Okay, so go back to wolf language.
Select all. Copy paste uh plot. Okay,
you got the nine in front. That's
incorrect.
Delete. Shift enter. There it is. Now,
now this you see the aspect ratio is not
one one. So we don't want that. So
usually when you do
introduc introductory math you want
aspect aspect ratio to be as
aspect ratio to be automatic automatic
will make it so that so that the ratio
is actually correct. You see now once
you got the correct ratio now you can
see this graphics is kind of too tall.
So you can you can uh what you can do is
you can just plot just part of it.
Okay. So actually let's leave it because
that's um
yeah. So let's leave it. So let's make
it 100.
So we're going to copy that.
Is this interesting? What are you doing?
It seems like you uh type some math
black magic. Uh these are yeah magic
they are uh you see uh famous saying is
that advanced technology is
indistinguishable
from magic that's what they say by this
author science fiction author um whose
name is author something uh I don't
really like that guy Ash ash Ashive um
his name is something like as
right you guys know the guy uh
so anyway so you see the the kosh oh god
we mean to plot uh yeah right this
is kosh there's also cinch
okay so
oh god what we doing so yeah so these
two are exactly the same yes how do you
know can you Actually, can you be sure?
Yes, of course. All you have to do is
just um
so let's put aspect ratio here. Aspect
ratio
auto uh automatic.
Okay. Why don't I Why do I not have a uh
completion? I mean, um Well, I do.
Okay. So
let's put that there. But also I want
this to be
kosh. So you're going to you're going to
have a list of graphics. Okay. So the
first graphics is that the second graph
is that. Okay. So I want to plot that.
Can you do that? Copy it. Copy. So we
can be sure these two coincide.
You see there's
because they are defined to they are
exactly the same thing and press control
shift N to to make it um type set. Okay.
Fantastic and beautiful.
There is ten. Yes.
Yes. There's a cinch cinch kosh tench
and a cinch kosh tench just like trick
functions. Uh so it's that's why they
are named hyperbolic trig functions
because they have analogous formulas
comparing to every trig functions or
identity. Okay. I don't really I didn't
know this until like amazing you know
after 30 years because today you got
Wikipedia you don't have that 30 years
ago. 30 years ago when I was learning
this you you know of course you have
textbooks and in calculus one two three
you know multi you know even if you took
one year of calculus you don't really
learn um the cinch kosh the hyperbolic
trick functions okay like after you took
one year of calculus you don't I mean
you you you rarely I mean you you you
you you might have some examples you
know it tell you you know since she's
define that you know Koshi's define that
but that's it that's you ever know about
it if you take one year of calculus
calculus you know ABCD from you know
introduction you know to differential
calculus to derivative to uh integrals
to multivariable calculus
you take calculus for one year you don't
learn much about the cinch like why are
they used why do you have that you don't
you don't learn it okay so [snorts] and
and then if you want You want to know
why are they called hyperbolic trig
functions? You don't know. You need to
go to library, spend few days to dig up
like old books, you know, 100 years old
or 200 years old, right? So, but today
you know Wikipedia will explain
everything and you and today you just
ask AI okay like uh you know we
demonstrated many times. Let's control J
for a new uh AI session. And let's just
ask
why is the math function hyperbolic sign
hyperbolic cosine? Why are they called
hyperbolic trig functions? Why trig?
They're called hyperbolic because they
parameterize a hyperola. Just like s and
cosine parameterize a circle. For the
unit circle, a point is cosine t sin t
satisfying x^2 + y^2= 1. For the unit
hyperola, it's cos t sinish t on x^2 -
y^2= 1. The names come from the 1750s.
Vincenzo Ricardi introduced them as
sinus cosis hyperbolic to mirror the
circular trig functions. They're called
trig functions because they share almost
identical properties. Addition formulas,
derivative relationships, d of sinish to
dx= cos, d of cos t= dx= sinish, the
identity cosine^ 2 x - sin^ 2 x= 1, and
even tailaylor series that look the same
except for sign patterns. They also link
directly through complex numbers. Sinish
of x= i sin of iix, for example.
Basically, they're the hyperbolic
analoges of the circular trig functions.
It's quite amazing, you know, quite
amazing. I've asked this before and you
know, I checked out Wikipedia before.
So, you know, so what what I'm saying is
that when I was learning this, you don't
get this. You you know, it is like you
have to spend days to read so many books
to actually summarize to get this kind
of information.
But since like 10 years ago, you go to
Wikipedia. Wikipedia has everything. And
today, you just ask AI. You don't even
have to type anything. Just talk and
you'll tell you. Okay. Just amazing. Um.
Okay. So, well, so, okay. So, what are
we doing? So, we we plotted it.
Uh, so let's uh let's let's do let's um
Yeah. So, we just plotted it. And what
did we do? Um
God.
Oh, yeah. So we did that.
Open it. Delete that. Close that. Okay.
So let's just move the figure here.
So this is the plot. So uh rename it
kosh.
Uh [sighs]
okay. So now what what did we do? We
don't want that co and syntax color that
showing browser. So we have
that fantastic you see this is new we
did today and over here that is 30 years
ago. Um
so we can delete the old. So today you
see the this is lossless WEBP image
format. So they are 10 kilobytes. Now
let's look at the other the old image
PNG 30 years ago. They are
uh not even 1 kilobyte. Okay, this is
very small back then because I need to
save space. So delete it. Uh delete it.
it no longer exist.
So we can just say the curve doesn't
matter.
So what am I doing? I uh you know so at
this rate it's going to this video to do
what I want to do is going to be three
hours
[gasps]
So because I spend all the time talking
uh do you recommend any book for me?
What?
So you seem very skilled to me. I just
know basic math. Okay. Do you recommend
any book for me? Are you making a web
page or something like that? God, you
must be new. Okay.
Well, yeah. So, you can go to my
website. So, this is my website. Visual
dictionary of special plane curves. This
is all about mathematics. Uh I did
actually it began 30 years ago, 1996.
the most popular page back then for 20
years on mathematics uh on saudi.org
okay on saudi.info info. So you can just
search for that, you'll find it. Uh
today it's being displays by Wikipedia
and all others. But this was the most
popular website, my website on this
topic for about 20 years. Okay. From
1996 to 2016. Okay.
Uh okay. So you can so if you want to
learn math high school level or calculus
level this you can still use my website
okay and each one of these curve they
are special they are called special
plane curves because they have many
properties there's uh you know there's
Wikipedia page for it you know
originally the Wikipedia page like 15
years ago they just copy they just copy
my website
but now they but actually a lot more
rich information.
So um
okay so yeah so you can check them out
back then people say Wikipedia are not
valid source today people say AI can be
trusted source yeah there's a phenomenon
like that okay so andra yeah so back
then when when Wikipedia began for the
first 10 years there's lots of nerds are
anti- Wikipedia
they will you know like oh that's That's
for idiots you know that's for kids we
are the actual professional for example
on programming languages
especially on lisp you know this
programming language you know in the
beginning there's some articles on lisp
right but these people the the like most
people they will say that you know
like Wikipedia is like for kids we are
professional you know whatever they say
on this is actually incorrect that's
actually true most of the time when
Wikipedia began, you know,
but it's too powerful. Anyway, so we uh
well, I'm not gonna talk about that
because otherwise I'm going to end up
talking for one hour about that and
going nowhere. I want to do what I want
to do today. Okay, so we talked about
the um
hyperbolic trig functions. Okay, so
let's copy that hyperbolic trig
functions. Why are they named so?
Okay, let's uh let me focus on what I
want to do. Okay, so because then it
makes me happy and when I'm happy, my
stuff is usually make you happy too.
Okay.
Uh search for visual. So let's make a
screenshot. So this is this is um
hyperbolic trick functions.
uh some kind of so rename the image
there. Okay. Now copy paste redo it.
Show in browser.
Fantastic. Okay. It's documented there.
That's the AI answer. But okay, now
let's go back to what I want to do. Um,
okay. So, I got a lot to do. Uh, so you
got rephrase that. Okay.
Close that.
Okay. So, yeah, we did that. So, what is
this?
Okay. So,
so what is going on is that uh let me
show you guys in a bit in a bit. Okay,
we can say that note um
okay so what so there's a interesting
property why is this curve interesting
because this is the shape of a hanging
chain okay so whenever you have cables
or whatever uh do I have a cable here no
where I got so many w okay okay or
there. Okay. So any chain, any rope
uh in their natural form will form this
curve. Exactly. Okay. So uh so so you
can see if you go to science museums,
they will have demonstration toys and
there's a famous uh gate the gateway of
ark at Missouri
is in the shape of cat katenary. Okay.
But they invert inverted it.
Okay. But that is not the case for uh
the suspension bridge. That the
suspension bridge that shape is
parabola. Okay. Uh
actually I'm not sure about that but I
think so. Um
let's ask AI. I want to
verify that today. AI is so convenient.
Okay. Uh, where is my AI panel? God,
too many browser windows
is suspension bridge
table has the form of parabola. Okay.
Yes.
Yes. The main cables of sus of a
suspension bridge typically form or
closely approximate a parabola. Okay.
Fantastic. [laughter]
Why a parabola not a catinary? Okay. It
actually knows what you are trying to
ask ask because this is a common
question when when when you study these
things. Okay. it actually knows the
context.
So uh let me uh so
okay so
so remove this this idiotic you know
it's claimed in publications
uh suspens suspension bridge cable has
the form of parabola okay something like
that
Uh
so then here is the old website. This
website is from like 30 years ago. It's
interesting. Some of this website is
still alive. Uh so that you know that
website explains why. Uh
okay. What what am I doing? I don't
know. So I got a so I got so many things
to do here. So delete that.
Worthwhile to note. Okay. So worthwhile.
So remove that. Worthwhile to note.
Okay.
Delete that.
Uh redo that picture. Okay. So then you
need to redo this picture. Now what this
picture shows is that
so
how do you explain? So if you have a
exponential curve now exponential curve
is e raised to x is a variable. So
that's a exponential curve. Okay. So if
you
if you shine a light ray from above the
curve and hit it and it bounce off
then it will form this shape and this
shape is a is a catenary. Okay. So
there's a relation between the
exponential curve and the catinary.
Okay, do you guys see what I'm saying?
So you see one curve is like that. The
other one is the um exponential curve.
And I don't have a page for exponential
curve.
So um God, I got a lot to do.
Okay, I'm um
Okay, good luck. Uh
improve my website CSS. No, not really.
You say that only because you are too
young. You are kind of too young. Uh
okay. So, what am I doing? Let's see.
Okay. Plain curve books. Okay. So,
let me show you guys some plain curve
books. Okay.
So, if you want to read about this, you
go to there's a collection of the best
books on plank curves. But today
actually it's not they are not really
worth it because today really you just
read Wikipedia and ask AI. Okay, it
beats all these uh books.
Uh so plank curve introductions. So what
are we reference? Okay, plank curve
books. Okay, so what I want to do so
this is a collection of plank curve
books from 1990s. Okay, these are the
best ones. Uh and what I want to do is
uh let's go to talk show
today's talk show and what so there is
the link go to it I want to replace all
these um
figure this unicode star
those are called uh the name of which is
growing star okay I want to replace them
by thumb up because the thumb up has
more universal meaning. You see the
thumb up, you know what it means, but
the glowing star less. Okay, I'm using
the star to indicate this a book I
recommend. So, you see there's a little
star.
So, replace growing star with
uh
So do it, do it, do it. Okay, that's all
of them showing browser. Fantastic.
Okay,
so rename star bullet
uh
Okay. So, let's use the thumb up.
Meanwhile,
I want to uh
meanwhile. So,
so let's get back to the Emacs.
So, let's go to find
ghost goland script. I want to find all
the occurrences of this star. Uh,
actually,
no. So actually let's just go to talk
show
and uh and call
s find count.
So you want to find the star and uh
greater than let's say three. So you
want to find all pages that contain the
star more than three of them. Okay. So
that's a emac.
Uh, wow. That's fast.
Oh, okay. So, that was fast.
HTTP status code. Let's show in browser.
Let's see what is this page about.
Here's a full list. Those with a star
sign are most frequently used.
Okay, that's [laughter]
that's what I use it for. So here's a
documentation of HTTP status code.
And what about this page? What do I use
the star on that page for? Unicode
stars. Okay, that's expected. That's
this star. Okay. Uh and and okay, close
that. And
comic code fun. Okay, that's my unic
code blog.
Okay.
Uh, okay. We So, we found
all occurrences of the star on about
13,000
HTML files. Well, actually info, which
is 9,000 HTML files. So, so you only
found this occurrence. So close them.
Um, actually reopen them.
Al print to make a screenshot of it. So,
so we have a record of it. So, we can
actually
put a screenshot here. Okay. So, now
what's what's next? So, we did that.
Close it. Okay. Close it. Close it.
Okay. So what is the next thing we want
to do? So
yeah. So that is done that now. So one
of the great book for plank curves is
this one a book of curves by eh
lockwood.
Okay that's written in like 1961.
Okay. So I want to make it a new page.
Uh the reason you want to make it a new
page is because
because when you have a a page so so
right now this page has a lot of books
recommendations
but when you want to talk about a
specific book you cannot link to it. uh
you kind of can but you make you you
have to make a jump but I prefer to have
indep independent page okay so let's
just make um
make a new page for this book okay
that's one thing the other thing I want
to do is to add a H2 title H2 header for
each of this book so you can see each
section you know there's a book cover
and but there's a title but there's no
like big heading. So I want to have that
big heading. So can you guys see what
I'm talking about? Can you if I shrink?
You see you you got quite a few books
more books. You see I want a big H2
heading for each. Okay. So let's do
that.
So
how how how do you do this? Um,
okay. So, title. God.
So, these are the titles. Oh, this
they don't look so good. Each one has a
Amazon link. So,
Okay, let's make the Amazon link on the
line by itself.
Okay, so go to the top find replace that
by
that. Okay, do it.
Do it. Okay, so it's all done. Now
title. Um
you see now I use title bold. So this is
title uh you clite and beyond. Now I
believe we can use a CSS trick so that
you don't actually to say uh boat there.
But anyway
uh how do you do this? God this is not
so easy. So here is the picture of the
book. This is uh this is quite a uh
geometry uklide and beyond. Okay. It's
available on Amazon.
Yeah. So this book is graduate
or kind of advanced undergraduate. Okay.
So this is a undergraduate text in
mathematics, geometry, uklide and
beyond. They talk about basically they
show you uh abstract algebra.
Uh they prove that you cannot circle a
square things like that. Okay. Uh, and
oh well, Emacs.
Um,
God, what am I doing?
So, uh, God, what am I doing? So, you
want to
T
[sighs]
I wanted to add a H2
for each, but it's not so easy.
because
let's try this again. Let's see what is
the uh
how do I have them? Okay, so each title
always followed by
side class book. Okay, so that is good.
That is quite uh important okay to know.
So each title always followed by
site class book. Is that true for all?
Yes. Yes. Okay. So in that case we can
use a marco keyboard macro. Okay. So
let's go to the beginning of title.
Search for title. Okay. So now let's do
this. Okay. Now copy this to register.
So we can paste it to register. Okay.
Look at the pink window. It'll show my
Emacs command. So, we're going to do
some advanced Emacs.
So, so now let's start record. Uh, let's
say,
okay, start recording.
Search for Let's do this. Li
B title.
Okay. Then
jump. Jump. Okay. Then
start selection.
Go to the end of bracket. Go to the
beginning of bracket. Copy.
Now
go to the beginning of line and
and do that. Jump to the beginning of
bracket. Now paste new line. New line.
Now add
H2.
Okay. Then
then what you want to do, you want to
pass it. Okay.
Okay. Now stop recording.
Stop.
Okay. So now if you show in browser, you
can see we got the title for the first
one.
Okay. So now if we call the um keyboard
macco again uh you can see the command
in the ping window. It will repeat.
Okay. So let's see.
Do it. Fantastic. The tricsection
problem. So now do it.
Do it. Do it. Do it. Do it. Do it.
Fantastic. Do
two
do two do two do two do two do two do
two do two do two do two do two do
okay then there's none so showing
browser
so can you see we added the title
fantastic the H2 title to all of them
the tric sectors there
a book of curves there catalog of
spatial plank fantastic and Beautiful.
Uh then history of math books. So
fantastic. Okay. Now back to the
original font size. This font is too
big.
Okay. We Okay. So we added the H2. Now
what? Now there is more things we want
to fix because
this idiotic format um
this you know you for example this image
should be after the title.
So can we do that? So go to the top
search for image tag.
Uh and that thumb that thumb
icon is not good. It should be, you
know, it should be inside.
Okay. So, let me let me try to do this.
Okay. So record
search
img space src.
Okay. Now move to the end. Now delete.
Now move to the end twice. Now enter.
Enter. Paste.
Okay. That that that's one done.
And now
stop recording Marco. Okay. Now call the
Marco. Fantastic. Do it again. Yes. Yes.
Yes. Yes. Yes. Yes. Yes. Yes. Yes. Yes.
Yes. Yes. Fantastic. There's no more.
Now
we refresh you see you should see the
title goes up uh before the image. Okay
for example the title will go before the
image for all of them. Okay refresh
fantastic
encyclopedia dictionary of mathematics.
There's no image for that one. Well, we
can add it. But that's um that's a
that's a that's a great great uh you
know this this thick this this thick
these two together. Yeah. Um but again
today they are kind of useless. Okay.
like Wikipedia has all the information
they know these uh these two volumes
and much much more because this this is
done in 1990s so 1987
you know so it's missing
30 years of progress of mathematics
uh and in past 30 years there's a lot
new a lot news okay but anyway but this
But you know so this encyclopedia their
content
will you need to be a graduate you know
you you need to have a math degree to
basically understand them. Okay.
So anyway we did that we we we did the
you know the the um you know we made the
title we we made the format much better
now. And let's search for the book. Uh
that book I was looking at the it's
called um by
by this guy
whose name contains the word wood. Eh
lock wood. Okay. Now this I want to make
it a uh a page by itself.
The tric sectors. Okay. a book of
curves. So, should I
Yeah, let's leave it. I think let's
leave it. Okay. So,
H2 for each. We did that. Did Okay.
Change start to thumb. We did that.
Delete
uh new page. Leave it. Okay. And this is
functional programming.
Delete that image. We this redo. Okay.
So we need to redo this image.
Okay. So that image
in order to redo this image we need to
you need a lot of my packages.
Oh yeah. And we can part that.
Okay. Let's plot that first because
that's that's building much easier. Uh
surface of re revolution. Okay. Surface
surface area this surface plot.
So I don't remember what is the function
name but we can uh see it here by just
going into
what is list surface plus pl plus 3D
there's no uh examples
examples
basic. Oh, okay. This kind of boring
computer graphic stuff. What we want is
mathematical functions
computational geometry. No, we want
>> [snorts]
>> um
we want to go to
homepage.
Wrame documentation homepage. Okay. Then
we want to go to
graphs and network higher mathematical
computation visualization and graphics.
We want function
visualization because we want surface of
revolution
uh revolution plot 3D. Okay. So that's
how they name it.
Okay, let's copy that.
What?
Shift enter.
Why is that taking so long?
Okay, that's that's nice.
Okay. Well, the phone is too large.
King, can we just um
Okay, So what we going to do now is to
Yeah. So we want the cutenary
surface of revolution.
Okay. So you need to plot that
Okay. So that's one of them. Uh but here
you want to plot kosh.
Um yeah. So kosh. Okay.
Okay. I gotta go. Uh,
okay.
Uh,
We didn't we didn't get too far.
So,
so co let's say 0 to three. This is
theta. We know we don't want theta. Oh,
wait. There are two values here.
T2. Wait, how did it get theta?
theta 0 to pi. So
that's right. So we want the theta. So
uh let's say two. Okay. So
let's see what we get.
Shift enter.
Okay. So this is
surface of revolution but we are using
the wrong axis.
So we want to revolve it on the x axis.
So this is revolving around the y axis.
So how do you revolve it around the x
axis?
There must be a example somewhere.
Scope options boundary style color
function.
Oh god. So alternatively
we need to turn our function 90 degrees.
Oh, so you can do it that way.
Let's just try this. Okay, let's just
try this.
What
does it
does that work
kind of
Mathematica? Yes,
I just started learning. Yeah.
So,
[sighs]
Oh god, I need to figure this out. But
but I got to go
now. You need to think. Okay, so
you need to think about this. But right
now I'm distracted.
Or alternatively
the easiest way to get to this to work
is simply
uh you just look at bunch of uh
examples. Actually the easiest way just
ask AI. Okay.
So either have to think carefully about
this, read this in detail, this this
thing or just ask AI. Let's just ask AI
because
um
because right now I'm don't know what
I'm doing.
Uh [sighs and gasps] where is my AI?
Okay.
In wolfframe language
plot
kosh
surface of revolution
shift enter no just enter you know I'm
not thinking but actually I know I know
the parametric equation because I
already have it on my website
you see so revolution plot so box ratio
axis so this is I don't think this is
correct copy that nice version
recommended basic version so
no I want to revolve around the y axis
oh I didn't say there
so I wanted to Say
I want to say revolve surface of
revolution
revolve around y uh the x-axis.
So, what does it
That's not I don't think that's it.
God, a huge ship.
No, that's not what we want. What we
want is like that. Okay. So for that
actually we have the uh equation. The
equation is that just plot it and you
you can do it. Okay. Like copy
and plot. Okay. But here we are plotting
it
um you know we are plotting it using
parametric plot.
But what we were trying to do is using
this revolution plot 3D so that
automatically
so that you can plot the surface of
revolution of any function.
You don't have to manually figure out
the actual parameters because here you
are doing a parametric plot you which
you have to you have to figure out uh
the parametric equation which is this uh
co cosine co s and u which can be
difficult okay to figure out exactly
what they are. So when you but you can
use the revolution plot 3D which just
give a function that will plot it. Okay.
But now the question the the the thing
is that um yeah so actually so
well let me try something. Okay let me
just try uh this instead of kosh it's
got uh kosh
arc kosh. Okay,
that will do it. There it is. So, we
kind of did it. Okay, so arc kosh is the
inverse function of kosh. Okay, so let
me adjust it. So, you can can you see
can you use it to see we are getting
like part of that?
You see because only only a small
fraction you know we can we can make it
like that if we enlarge the um
parameters let's say nine
nine shift enter
okay so we get nine so
yeah so we got that but then you don't
have the other part yeah
I mean the bottom
So anyway so arc kosh is the inverse
function of of the kosh okay now do you
guys understand you see we are trying to
do surface of revolution of this
function okay this function uh let's dd
that because that's um so but by default
it revolve this around the z-axis okay
but we wanted to revolve this around the
x-axis
Okay. So we want to get um we want to
get something like that. [sighs]
Um so one way to do it is you figure out
in this revolution plot 3D
shift controlN you figure out if there
is a uh like option like which axis you
want to revolve it around.
Okay. So
but um
but I don't seem to have that uh option
here. Okay.
So if you don't have that option, what
you do is you then then you need
mathematically turn this function,
you know, turn this function looks like
that. You you want it turn it sideways.
You want to turn it 90 degrees. So you
can rotate it 90°
which in other words but you can see so
in other words in in other words you you
could get the same effect by having
the arc kosh function which is the
inverse of kosh. Okay it so you see like
that.
So now if you revolve this around the um
you know if if you revolve this around
you know the default Z-axis
then that that's what we get that's what
that's how we got that
okay so now you just uh you need this be
bigger okay so let's say
19 what will happen to
Yeah, you
let's say 1009.
Anyway, so anyway, I got to go uh like
today we didn't do much, you know. So,
we were going to do
uh we
we were going to do lots of things.
Let's see. Uh
yeah. Well, we were going to do like
several um
we were going to do
we were going to talk about Oh not
this page. Uh showing brows. So we were
talking about JavaScript. We didn't do
that at all.
uh JavaScript exponential functions
JavaScript
cinch co and we didn't even plot cinch
but h I got to go okay so we kind of
didn't go far so I was going to do I was
going to add images for all these for
reference so when people use JavaScript
functions they can easily see you know
as a reminder what the graph looks like.
So that was part of what we're going to
do and quite a few other things because
in JavaScript there's uh in JavaScript
there's quite a few interesting things
going on because um for example the
JavaScript
30 bits integer you know they got these
functions funky functions
uh okay but that's it for today and
power and roots uh you know so I was
going to add graphics for that anyway.
So let's do that another time then.
Today we kind of just fumbled around
around these um hyper hyperbolic trig
functions. Okay. And we didn't
accomplish much because
because one of the most actually uh I
should do that but because one of the
most spectacular
image about katenary is this one uh
which I didn't do but
you know I showed you my old wuam
language notebook is there but
we actually should I should show you the
code um to actually do it, but I have to
load it and stuff. Okay, that's it for
today. Bye, guys. Thanks for watching.
Bye.